aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Dagwon managed to get Gedo out of Dag Base,
다그 베이스 내에 침입한 게도를 간신히 쫓아내긴 했으나
but Power Dagwon was pushed into a dire crisis by his powerful attack.
그 강력한 공격에 의해 파워 다그온은 절대 절명의 위기에 빠져갔다
However, Lian flew here from the other side of the Space and they were saved.
하지만 우주 저편에서 라이안이 날아와 위기에서 탈출
Finally, Dagwon defeated Gedo.
다그온은 마침내 게도에게 승리했다
Only Mado is left of the Warugaia Brothers.
와르가이아 형제도 남은 건 마도 한 명 뿐이야
Our reassuring comrade Lian is back too, and it's like attaching wings to a tiger!
든든한 동료, 라이안도 돌아왔으니 호랑이에 날개를 단 격이구만
Let's do our best to the end.
마지막까지 힘내야지
But, there are probably many events going on on Earth since it's almost Christmas, and no one knows our hardships!
그치만 말이야 우리가 고생하는 것도 모르고 지금쯤 지구는 크리스마스로 모두들 떠들석하겠구만
Don't murmur, Shin!
궁시렁대지마, 신
We Dagwon are the Santa Claus who is taking peace as a present to Earth!
우리 다그온은 지구에 평화라는 선물을 줄 산타크로스잖아
I see. Geki does sometimes say good things!
과연, 게키도 가끔은 좋은 소리 하네요
Sometimes? No, I always do!
가끔?
자주 한다구!
Senpai, it seems that we'll receive a wonderful present too.
선배, 우리에게도 멋진 선물이 올 것 같아요
What's that, Rai?
무슨 일이야, 라이?
Just now, I got a transmission that a fleet of the Space Police Organization has departed to capture Mado!
지금 막 우주 경찰 기구의 함대가 마도 체포를 위해 출발했다는 연락이 들어왔습니다
A fleet of the Space Police Organization?!
우주 경찰 기구의 함대?
Alright! It's like we already won!
좋았어! 이제 승부는 난 거나 다름없군!
Sargasso is visible on the radar.
레이더에 사르갓소를 포착했습니다
There are no signs of attack.
공격해올 낌새는 없습니다
Great. Send to Mado:
좋아, 마도에게 송신해라
If you follow our orders and surrender....
우리 명령에 따라 항복하면…
-What's going on?
-An odd gravitational occurred! Unable to control Spaceship!
-무슨 일인가?
-이상 중력파 발생! 함 조작 불능!
No way! That's impossible!
말도 안돼!
그런 일이…!
H- help us!
부, 부딪힌다!
Miraculous Brave Heroes
기적의 용자들
Warugaia Seijin Mado
Appears
와르가이아 성인 마도
등장
I am not going to surrender to the Space Police Organization.
우주 경찰 기구 따위에게 순순히 잡힐 내가 아니다
Those numerous prisoners were all garbage.
그 많던 죄수 놈들은 모두 도움도 안되는 쓰레기들이었다
Watch this Mado take down Dagwon in the afterlife.
이 마도가 다그온을 해치우는 걸 저승에서 잘 보고 있거라
Go, Mado.
가라, 마도…
A hallucination, I guess.
환청인가…
No one other than me is alive in this Sargasso.
이 사르갓소에 나 이외에 살아남은 녀석은 없어
Dagwon, this Mars will be your grave.
다그온이여… 이 화성이 너희들 무덤이다
Annihilated...
전멸…
It seems that they didn't even have time to send an SOS.
SOS를 보낼 틈도 없었던 것 같습니다
Who could've done that?
대체 누가…?
No way...
설마?!
Only Mado can do that.
마도의 짓이라고밖에 생각할 수 없어
I can't believe that! He took down the whole fleet of the Space Police Organization by himself?!
미, 믿겨지지 않아요! 혼자서 우주 경찰 기구의 함대를 산산조각내다니…
There's no point in being shocked!
계속 놀라고만 있어봤자 소용없어!
After all, only we are going to take that bastard down!
역시 녀석을 해치우는 건 우리 뿐이란 거잖아!
What are you doing, Rai?!
뭐하는 거야, 라이!
Are you drunk driving?!
제대로 조종 안할래!
N- no! The controls aren't working!
트, 틀렸습니다! 조종간이 말을 안 들어요!
Unable to control!
조종 불능!
We're being pulled near Mars by a strong gravitational force!
엄청난 중력으로 화성 쪽으로 끌려가고 있습니다!
To Mars?! What's the meaning of this?
화성으로?! 어떻게 된 일이지?!
Th-this gravity can be only explained as an artificial gravity!
이, 이 중력은… 인공적으로 만들어진 거라고밖에 생각할 수 없어요!
Artifical? I see, no doubt about it. It's all Mado's work!
인공적?
그래, 틀림없어! 마도가 한 짓이야!
We're going to crash on Mars!
이대론 화성에 격돌합니다!
Rai! Raise your spiritual wave!
라이, 정신파를 높여!
Y-yes, Ryu senpai!
네, 네
류 선배!
What a strong gravity!
엄청난 중력이야!
The fleet of the Space Police Organization must've been annihilated by this gravity!
우주 경찰 기구의 함대도 이 강력한 중력으로 전멸당한 게 틀림없어!
We're going to be broken into pieces along with Dag Base!
다그 베이스 째로 우리도 산산조각나고 말 거야!
It seems that the source of this gravitational wave is below that crater!
저 크레이터의 지하에 중력파 발생원이 있는 것 같습니다
Damn! Can't we do anything, Rai?!
젠장! 어떻게 안 되겠냐, 라이?!
I'm doing this desperately!
저, 저도 필사적으로 노력하고 있어요!
Calm down, Rai! Your spirit will be dispersed if you are afraid!
침착해, 라이! 공포심을 가지면 마음이 흐트러지고 말아!
Believe in your strength and concentrate your spirit to Dag Base!
자신의 힘에 자신을 가지고 정신을 다그 베이스에 집중시켜!
Yes, sir!
네!
We're somehow saved...
그럭저럭 살았군
No, we aren't! Launch anchor!
그렇겐 안돼!
닻(anchor) 발사!
While Rai is holding Dag Base, we must destroy the source of this gravitational wave!
라이가 다그 베이스를 붙잡고 있는 사이에 중력파 발생원을 파괴해야해!
Alright, I'll go!
좋아, 내가 간다!
Wait, En!
기다리세요, 엔!
Magma is boiling under the crater! Approaching it is too dangerous!
크레이터 내부는 마그마가 작열하고 있어요 다가가는 건 너무 위험해요!
Hmph, to hell with danger!
흥, 이제와서 위험이고 잣이고 알게 뭐냐!
En!
엔!
Stop, En!
기다려, 엔!
You just can't stop him.
막아도 소용없다니까
You know his personality.
저녀석의 성격은 잘 알고 있잖냐
En.
엔…
Geki?
게키…?
-Are you here to bid farewell?
-Well, maybe.
-뭐야, 배웅 나온 거야?
-뭐, 그런 셈이지
Hmph, I'm not ruined to the extent that you need to worry about me!
흥, 네가 걱정할 정도로 영락(零落)하진 않다구
Geki, you bastard...
게, 게키… 이자식…
En, this is too much for you. Leave this operation to me.
엔, 네겐 너무 힘들어 이 임무는 나한테 맡겨라
Damn!
젠장…!
If something ever happens to you, Ms. Maria will be sad.
만약 네게 무슨 일이 생긴다면 마리아 씨가 슬퍼할 테니까 말이야
Yeah, I'm too cool.
내가 봐도 난 참 멋지다니까
Hmph, persistent brats.
흥, 끈질긴 놈들
Well, if they died too easily, it wouldn't be fun at all.
하긴, 그렇게 간단히 죽어버려선 재미가 없겠지만 말이야
-That is definitely Mado!
-Let's see how we do!
-역시 마도야!
-두고봐라!
En?!
-엔?!
What happened, En?!
어떻게 된 거야, 엔?!
P- probably something happened.
어, 어떻고 뭐고…
That Geki bastard went in here and...
게키 녀석이 끼어들어서…
Geki?!
게키가?!
We're going out too! We're not letting Mado do as he wants!
우리도 출격이다! 언제까지고 마도 뜻대로 내버려둘 순 없어!
Yeah!
-오우!
We entrust Dag Base to you, Rai.
다그 베이스를 부탁한다, 라이
Ryu senpai.
류 선배
I will protect Dag Base no matter what!
다그 베이스는 반드시 제가 지켜 보이겠습니다!
What?!
아니?!
What's wrong, everyone?!
왜 그래, 얘들아?!
We cannot fly because of the effect of the gravitational wave!
중력파의 영향으로 비행 능력을 발휘할 수 없어!
What?!
뭐라고?!
It seems that the wings of Dagwon have been torn.
날개를 뜯긴 다그온이란 거다
Don't make me laugh! We can fight even if we can't fly!
웃기지 마라! 날 수 없어도 싸울 순 있다구!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어
Star Burn!
스타 번!
Do you think you can take me down with that? Now come, Dagwon!
이런 걸로 날 해치울 수 있다고 생각하느냐?! 자, 와라! 다그온!
That's what I was going to do! Fire Blaster!
바라는 바다! 파이어 블래스터!
Damn! The only one remaining is that Mado! If I take him down...
젠장! 남은 적은 저 마도 한 명뿐 저녀석만 쓰러뜨리면…!
This is overwhelmingly hot!
엄청난 고열(高熱)이군!
Why you-! This is nothing to me!
이놈, 이깟 것쯤이야!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
This is a news flash. According to Greenwich Observatory, a huge piece of rock is...
임시 뉴스를 전해드리겠습니다 그리니치 천문대의 관측에 의해 발견된 거대한 암석의 조각이
... now near Mars and it is still approaching the Earth with a high speed.
화상 부근까지 도달했고 그 이후에도 지구를 향해 빠른 속도로 접근중이라고 합니다
Just in case, the UN has opened an emergency response center and an international conference is now in session.
UN에서는 최악의 경우를 생각해 긴급대책본부를 설치하고 각국 대표와 협의에 들어갔습니다
After today, this huge meteorite...
오늘 이후, 이 거대 운석에 대해…
Grandpa! The huge meteorite is actually Sargasso, which aliens use as their stronghold.
할아버지 거대한 바위 조각 말이야 우주인들이 본거지로 삼고 있는 사르갓소야
They are coming to invade Earth! No doubt about it!
녀석들이 지구에 쳐들어오려는 거야 틀림없어!
Sargasso's at Mars now? Everyone must be fighting desperately against the Warugaia Seijin.
사르갓소가 화성까지… 분명 지금쯤 모두들 필사적으로 와르가이아 성인과 싸우고 있을 거야
Please tell me. Why specifically do they have to do this?
가르쳐줘 어째서 그 애들만이 위험에 처해야 하는 거야?
Why?!
어째서?!
Maria...
마리아…
Grandpa.
할아버지…
I guess it's alright not to worry since they're Dagwon...
다그온이 있으니까 걱정없을 거라고 생각하지만
... but is Earth alright?
지구는 괜찮겠지?
Look at this forest.
이 숲을 보렴
Even in the snowy winds of winter, trees and floras endure and they sprout and bloom beautiful new flowers again in Spring.
겨울의 풍설(風雪)에도 나무와 화초는 꼼짝않고 견뎌내고 다시 봄이 되면 새로운 싹이 터서 아름다운 꽃을 피운단다
It's the same for humans.
인간도 마찬가지란다
Whatever chaos approaches, they don't become discouraged.
그 어떤 혼란이 닥쳐오더라도 그리 간단히 꺾이진 않는단다
No! At this rate...!
안돼, 이대로는…!
Lian, I'll help too!
라이안, 나도 도울게!
Alright! Rai is doing his best inside!
좋아, 라이도 안에서 노력하고 있을 거야
We will protect Dag Base together!
우리도 다그 베이스를 지키자!
Armor Buster!
아머 버스터!
Magma Blast!
마그나 블래스트!
Shadow Big Shuriken!
섀도우 대 수리검!
We did it!
성공이다!
What?! My shuriken!
아니?!
내 수리검이!
Is he invincible?!
저놈, 불사신인가?!
No way. Mado is enlarging himself!
마, 말도안돼! 마도가 거대화해가고 이어!
Look with two eyes open, Dagwon!
잘 보거라, 다그온!
What are you going to do?!
무슨 짓을 할 셈이냐?!
Un- unbelievable!
미, 믿겨지지 않아!
What destructive power!
엄청난 파괴력이야!
It'll be your turn next!
다음은 너희들 차례다!
At this rate...
이대로 가면…!
That damn Geki! He's all talk and no show!
게키 녀석! 잘난 듯이 지껄이더니 뭐하고 있는 거야?!
Where is the source of the gravitational wave?!
중력파 발생원은 어디지?!
Within a few minutes, I'll melt away with Drill Liner!
앞으로 몇분 후면 드릴 라이너 째로 녹아버리고 말아!
Liner Tackle!
라이너 태클!
Beast-King Slash!
아왕참!
What a strong bastard!
엄청난 녀석이야!
His power got even stronger!
힘까지 한층 더 상승해 있어!
Damn! Only one... If we take down Mado, then everything'll be over!
제길! 녀석만… 마도만 해치우면 모든게 끝나!
With all my power! Magma Blast!
전력을 다해 간다! 마그마 블래스트!
Thank you, Dagwon!
이거 고맙군, 다그온!
Wh-what?!
아, 아니?!
He enlarged again!
또다시 커졌어!
I see!
그렇군!
Mado is absorbing the energy we used to attack to make his own energy!
마도는 우리가 공격한 에너지를 흡수해서 자신의 에너지로 바꾸고 있는 거야!
Then does it mean that attacking will only make Mado stronger?
그럼 우리가 공격하면 할수록 마도를 파워업시킬 뿐이라는 거야?!
No way!
그럴수가!
Which means that no matter how you squirm, you cannot take this Mado down!
다시말해, 아무리 발버둥쳐도 이 마도를 해치울 순 없단 말이다!
Damn!
젠장!
Dagwon fools, the true target of the Mado Super Light Wave made by absorbing your energy is...
다그온 놈들아 너희들이 준 공격 에너지를 흡수해서 만든 이 마도 초광파! 진정한 표적은…
There!
저곳이다!
The Earth?!
지구?!
-I- it can't be!
-Unforgivable!
-서, 설마?!
-용서 못한다!
It seems that you guys have a tradition of giving a present on Christmas Night.
너희들의 별에선 크리스마스에 선물을 주는 풍습이 있는 것 같더군
After all, this is the Christmas present that I give to the Earth!
요컨대 이건 내가 지구에게 보내는 크리스마스 선물이다!
Don't make us laugh! We're not letting you do that!
웃기지 마라! 그런 짓을 하게 둘 것 같냐?!
Damn!
젠장…!
I... I can't do it anymore!
이, 이제 다 틀렸어!
It's all over.
이제 끝장이야…
M- Ms. Maria...
마, 마리아 씨…
Damn...! I can't give up here!
제길…! 여기서 포기할 순 없어!
I must protect the Earth where Ms. Maria is! That is my mission!
마리아 씨가 있는 지구를 지켜야 해! 그게 내 사명이야!
That must be the source of the gravitational wave!
저게 중력파 발생원?!
I count on you, En!
뒤는 부탁한다, 엔!
Drill Attack!
드릴 어택!
Dear stupid humans of the Earth, Merry Christmas!
지구의 어리석은 인간 놈들이여 메리 크리스마스!
Eat this!
받아라!
What?!
아니?!
Dag Base activated! All functions restored!
다그 베이스 기동! 모든 기능이 회복됐습니다
Geki senpai has managed to destroy the source of the gravitational wave!
게키 선배가 중력파 발생원 파괴에 성공한 거예요!
How was that?! Did you see, En?!
어떠냐!
봤냐, 엔?!
Geki. I see you again!
게키, 다시 봤다!
My turn this time!
이번엔 내 차례구만!
Hmph! You simply failed to die... You may feast your eyes on the present you'll receive in hell!
흥, 죽다 살아난 녀석이… 저승길 선물이나 잘 봐 두거라!
Rai! Super Blazing Fusion!
라이, 초화염합체다!
But what if Mado absorbs Super Fire Dagwon's huge amount of energy?
하지만… 슈퍼 파이어 다그온의 초 거대 에너지를 마도에게 흡수당할 우려가…
Then I'll emit so much power, that he cannot possibly absorb it!
그렇다면 전부 흡수 못할 정도의 힘을 내면 돼!
Come! Lian! Gunkid!
와라!
라이안, 건키드!
Understood.
알았습니다
Super Blazing Fusion Light Wave...
초화염합체광파!
Fire!
발사!
Super Blazing Fusion!
초화염합체!
Super Fire Dagwon!
슈퍼 파이어 다그온!
This is like killing two birds with one stone.
이게 바로 일석 이조로군
I'll make the Earth disappear with you!
네놈과 함께 지구를 날려주마!
No matter who it is, nobody will lay a finger on our Earth!
그 누구도… 우리 지구에 손가락 하나 댈 수 없다!
I'll show you the infinite power hidden within Super Fire Dagwon!
슈퍼 파이어 다그온에게 숨겨진 무한대의 힘! 끌어내 보이겠다!
Do- do you feel something, Lian?
뭐, 뭔가 느껴지지 않아, 라이안?!
M- my body is burning hot!
모, 몸이 불타오르는 것처럼 뜨거워!
Die! Super Fire Dagwon!
죽어라, 슈퍼 파이어 다그온!
En senpai!
엔 선배!
What are you going to do?!
어쩔 셈이야?!
The fusion of a steel body and burning spirit!
강철의 몸에 뜨거온 혼!
Indomitable fighting spirit is the evidence of brave hero!
불굴의 투지는 용자의 증표!
Combine the three forces and shine!
3개의 힘을 하나로 합쳐, 빛나라!
The miraculous power of Dagwon!
기적의 다그온 파워!
Triangle Christmas Beam!
트라이앵글 크리스마스 빔!
Wh- what?
아, 아니?!
Impossible! Dagwon still had such power?
말도 안돼! 다그온에게 아직도 이런 힘이…
Dear Mado... You were just a hopeless crap after all.
마도여…결국 너도 도움이 되지 않는 쓰레기였구나
Who are you?!
누구냐?!
What does my identity mean to you anyway? Your duty is over. Farewell, Mado.
그걸 알아서 어쩔텐가? 너의 역할은 끝났다
작별이다, 마도
Wh- who are you?!
누, 누구냐?!
You must be...!
네놈은 대체…?!
Good job, En.
잘했다, 엔…
Geki...
게키...
We took down all the aliens of Sargasso at last.
이걸로 사르갓소의 우주인은 모두 해치웠어
It's a complete victory of us Dagwon!
우리 다그온의 완전 승리예요!
En!
엔!
En, hang in there!
엔, 정신차려
Now, let's get En into Dag Base.
자, 다그 베이스로 엔을 옮기자
Senpai!
선배!
Rai, you did a good job too.
라이, 너도 잘했다
That's not it! Look at Sargasso!
그게 아니구요
사르갓소가…!
What's wrong?
왜그래?
This is...
이, 이건…
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
kaze no naka no PRISM
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
Impossible! Now we've taken down Mado, and Sargasso transformed as if it's alive!
있을 수 없어요! 마도를 해치웠는데 사르갓소가 마치 살아있는 것처럼 변형하다니!
There's no time to think! We'll just have to destroy Sargasso at all!
가만히 생각하고 있을 틈은 없어! 이렇게 되면 사르갓소를 부숴버리는 거야!
The true ruler of aliens has revealed himself.
우주인의 진정한 지배자가 정체를 드러냈습니다
The name is Genocide. Everybody will be combined into Genocide!
그 이름은 제노사이드
모두 제노사이드에게 융합돼 버리고 말아요!
That time, something unbelievable has happened to me!
그 순간, 내 몸에 터무니없는 일이 벌어졌어!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Sargasso Explodes
다음회 용자지령 다그온
사르갓소 대폭발
En senpai and Dag Base are...!
엔 선배가 다그 베이스를!
Sargasso Explodes
사르갓소 대폭발